在面临被毁灭的氪星上 一位聪明的科学家将他的新生儿子放进太空船里
并将太空船驶向地球 这个小男孩被一对农村夫妇抚养长大
他成了地球最伟大的保护者 超人 可是当太空人发现了氪星残骸时 超人消失了
你将到很远的地方去 我的小凯尔
You will travel far, my little Kal-EI.
但我们永远不会离开你
But we will never leave you...
就算死亡已近在我们眼前
...even in the face of our deaths.
我会把我的力量给你
You will make my strength your own.
你会透过你的眼睛看见我的一生
You will see my life through your eyes...
如同我会透过我的眼睛看见你的一生
...as your life will be seen through mine.
儿子变成了父亲 父亲又变成了儿子
The son becomes the father, and the father the son.
《超人归来》
不管你的过去如何
In spite of your past...
我知道你是个好人
...I know you're a good man.
所有的好人
And all good men...
都有重新来过的机会
...deserve a second chance.
从我收到你的第一封信起…
From the moment I received your first letter...
我就知道你和其他人不同
...I knew you were not like the rest.
你开始什么都没有
You came from nothing...
经过了极大的努力才达到现在的地位
...and you worked so hard to get where you are.
其间也许犯了一些错误
You might have made a few mistakes.
加图德 看在上帝的份上
Gertrude, for God's sake!
见鬼 加图德 让我们进去
Damn it, Gertrude, let us in now!
你说过如果我帮你逃出去
You said that if I helped you get out of prison...
你就会对我很好的
...you'd take care of me.
而你的确做到了
And you have.
你让我感受到前所未有的快乐
You've shown me pleasures that I've never known.
所以你将得到…
That's why you deserve...
这一切
...everything.
我爱你
I love you...
雷克斯·路瑟
...Lex Luthor.
加图德 让我们进去 他是个骗子
Gertrude, let us in. He's a crook.
他不爱你呀 加图德
He doesn't love you, Gertrude!
他是个坏人 加图德
He's a monster! Gertrude!
- 你留着吧 - 哦 天啊
- You can keep that. - Oh, God.
其它的都是我的
The rest is mine.
结束了
We're done.
再见 玛莎
Bye, Martha.
哦 克拉克
Oh, Clark.
哦 我的孩子
Oh, my boy.
把那个东西弄走
Will you get that thing out of my face!
雷克斯 你的朋友让我感觉很不舒服
Lex, your friends give me the creeps.
监狱本来就不是舒服的地方
Prison is a creepy place, Kitty.
想要活下来的话 你就得跟一些牛鬼蛇神做朋友
One needs to make creepy friends in order to survive.
在里面 像我一个这么聪明的脑袋
Even a man with my vast talents is won'th less inside...
也不比一条香烟或口袋里一把利器值钱
...than a can'ton of cigarettes and a sharp piece of metal in your pocket.
你听过普洛米修斯的故事吗 你当然没听过
Do you know the story of Prometheus? No, of course you don't.
普洛米修斯从其它神那里偷了火的力量
Prometheus was a god who stole the power of fire from the other gods...
他把火给了人类
...and gave control of it to mortals.
也可以说 他给了我们科技 他给了我们力量
In essence, he gave us technology. He gave us power.
所以我们要去北极偷火？
So we're stealing fire? In the Arctic.
可以这么说 你想想 谁控制了科技谁就控制了世界
Actually, sort of. You see, whoever controls technology controls the world.
古罗马帝国因为造路而统治世界
The Roman Empire ruled the world because they built roads.
大英帝国因为造船而统治世界
The British Empire ruled the world because they built ships.
美国因为原子弹…等等
America, the atom bomb, and so on and so forth.
我想要的东西和普洛米修斯一样
I just want what Prometheus wanted.
听起来很棒 雷克斯 但你不是神
Sounds great, Lex, but you're not a god.
神只不过是披着红披风 整天飞来飞去的自私之徒
Gods are selfish beings who fly around in little red capes...
而不把他的力量与人类分享
...and don't share their power with mankind.
嘿 老板
Hey, boss.
我们找到了
We found something.
我不想当神
No, I don't wanna be a god.
我只想把火种带给人类
I just wanna bring fire to the people.
并且 我也要我自己那份
And I want my cut.
这是他以前的家吗？
Was this his house?
大部份人都会这么想
You might think so. Most would.
较正确的说法是
This is more of a monument to a long dead...
这是一个非常强大的 远古文明留下来的遗址
...and extremely powerful civilization.
他在这里得知他的身世
This is where he learned who he was.
当他迷惘时他在这里寻求方向
This is where he came for guidance.
可能…
Possibilities.
无限的可能
Endless possibilities.
你看起来好像你来过这里
You act like you've been here before.
我的儿子
My son...
你不记得我
...you do not remember me.
我是佐尔
I am Jor-EI.
我是你的父亲
I'm your father.
我已经死了几千年了
By now, I will have been dead many thousands of your years.
- 他把我当成他的儿子了 - 你是氪星惟一的幸存者
- He thinks I'm his son. - You are the only survivor of Krypton.
你前面的这些水晶里储存着
Embedded in the crystals before you is the total accumulation of all literature...
第28银河系里
...and scientific fact from dozens of other worlds...
数十个文明发展的所有文学和科学知识
...spanning the 28 known galaxies.
在这里会提出许多问题
There are questions to be asked.
在这个
Here in this...
隐密的堡垒
This Fortress of Solitude...
我们将共同追寻解答
...we shall try to find the answers together.
他看得到我们吗？
Can he see us?
不 他已经死了
No, he's dead.
我的儿子
So, my son...
凯尔
...Kal-EI...
问吧
...speak.
告诉我所有的事
Tell me everything...
从水晶开始
...starting with crystals.
乖孩子
Hey, boy.
周二 在支持者间…
On Tuesday, between support...
消防队员们的奋力扑救…
hindered the firefighting efforts for all those...
警察终于到来 但现场还是一片混乱
Police have finally arrived and it's still complete mayhem down here.
战事在最南边区域打响…
Fighting broke out in the southernmost region...
边境上小规模武器袭击时有发生
...with border fire and small-arms attacks prevalent.
别担心 我早上把它埋起来了
Don't worry, I buried it this morning.
想让他在大陪审团面前作证是徒劳的
It was futile trying to force him to testify before a grand jury.
妈妈？
Mom?
五年了
Five years.
如果你爸爸还在世 他绝不会让你走的
If your father was alive, he never would have let you go.
我差点放弃了希望
I almost gave up hope.
我以为我再也看不到你了
I just thought I would never see you again.
哦 克拉克
Oh, Clark.
你找到你要找的东西了吗？
Did you find what you were looking for?
我曾想过 满怀希望
I thought, hoped...
它也许还在那
...it might still be there.
你的家乡？
Your home?
那个地方像座坟场
That place was a graveyard.
我是唯一的生还者
I'm all that's left.
克拉克 宇宙是非常浩大的
Clark, the universe is a big place.
你不知道宇宙里还有谁在
And you don't know who's out there.
就算你真的是最后一个生存者
And even if you are the last...
你也不会孤单的
...you're not alone.
我知道
I know.
- 不好意思 - 小心
- Sorry. - Look out!
小心点
Watch out, will you?
- 不好意思 - 抱歉
- Excuse me. - Sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
你能不能小心点？
Great. Would you be careful?
- 吉米 - 克拉克先生 不 我是说 肯特先生
- Jimmy. - Mr. Clark! I mean, Kent! Mr. Kent!
欢迎回来 天啊
Welcome back! Oh, my God!
跟我… 你在这等着我马上回来
Hey, come... Wait right there. I'll be right back.
抱歉 各位 我还在找住的地方
Oh, hey, sorry, guys, I'm still looking for a place to live...
如果你知道
...if you know of anything reasonable.
在你后面 肯特先生 这个蛋糕是我自己做的
Behind you, Mr. Kent. I made it myself. It's a cake.
哦
Oh, it looks...
很好吃
...delicious.
欧森 生日派对小丑大屠杀事件的照片呢？
Olsen! Where are the photos of that birthday-clown-massacre thing?
我正在办 主编 看看谁回来了
I'm on it, chief. Hey, look who's back.
- 肯特？ - 嘿 主编
- Kent? - Hey, chief.
- 谢谢你让我回到这里来上班 - 别谢我
- Thank you for giving me my job back. - Don't thank me.
你应该谢诺姆·帕诺死的正是时候
Thank Norm Palmer for dying.
他也寿终正寝了
It was his time.
- 来帮你整理一下吧 - 欧森
- Let's get you set up, huh? - Olsen!
我该走了
Okay, so I gotta run...
不过我马上就回来 肯特先生
...but I will be back to check on you in a sec, Mr. Kent.
你知道露意丝在哪吗？
Oh, hey, do you know where I can find Lois?
自动点火前倒计时那段时间
The timing of this automated-ignition countdown...
是最不稳定的
...is the most precarious part of the launch.
露意丝·莲恩 星球日报
Lois Lane, Daily Planet.
你说新的太空梭将带领我们进入一个新纪元
You also stated that the shuttle will usher in a new era of travel...
连一个普通平民也付得起星际旅行的费用
...enabling the average person to afford transcontinental flights.
你能不能告诉我们一个实际的数字？
But can you tell us the exact price...
人均花费估计是多少？
...an "average person" will be expected to pay?
这个问题有不同的答案
The answer to that question is in your press packet.
地球被一团空气覆盖
The Earth is surrounded by a blanket of air...
我们称之为大气层
...which we call the atmosphere.
它延伸到…
It reaches over...
(普利兹奖 露意丝·莲恩)
(获奖作品： 为何这世界不需要超人)
(为何这世界不需要超人)
他看上去就像他的妈妈
Yeah. He looks just like his mom.
连行为举止都像 尤其在"闯祸"这方面
Already takes after her too, especially when it comes to getting into trouble.
妈妈？
Mother?
你离开太久可能不知道 露意丝·莲恩是个妈妈了
Oh, yeah, well, I guess you've been gone. Fearless reporter Lois Lane is a mommy.
我只是… 给我吧 很好
Oh, you know, I'll just... I'll take that. That's good.
- 抱歉 - 没关系 反正她很多
- Sorry. - No. She's got plenty.
- 等等 她结婚了吗？ - 是的
- Wait, she's married? - Yes.
也不算是 更像是超长的婚约
No. Not really. It's more like a prolonged engagement.
不过你可别问她何时结婚
But don't ask Miss Lane when they're tying the knot...
她很讨厌这个问题
...because she hates that question.
就好像要履行国家宇航局同样的安全条例？
Like this follow the same stringent safety guidelines set by NASA?
既然这是和空军联合的行动…
Since this is a joint venture with the Air Force...
你还好吗？ 你看起来好像需要去喝一杯
You all right? You look like you could use a drink.
这个地方真破烂 我们回来这里干吗？
This place is so tacky. Why are we back here?
咪咪 当你忙着修你的指甲 和在网上购买貂皮大衣时
Kitty, while you were doing your nails and ordering fur coats online...
我可是在忙着
...I was busy unlocking the secrets...
解开宇宙最先进文明的秘密
...of one of the most advanced civilizations in the universe.
本来不是有两只吗？
Werert there two of those?
你看 比起地球上使用的笨拙建筑方式
You see, unlike our clunky earthbound forms of construction...
氪星 也就是超人的母星
...the technology on Krypton, Supermars home world...
利用水晶的生长来建造东西
...was based on manipulating the growth of crystals.
听起来像在变魔术
Sounds like hocus-pocus to me.
对我们这些原始的脑袋来说
Well, naturally, to the primitive mind, any sufficiently advanced technology...
超先进的科技跟变魔术没什么两样
...would be indistinguishable from magic.
但想象一下 城市 车辆 武器…
But imagine: Cities, vehicles, weapons...
整个大陆
...entire continents...
所有的一切
...all grown.
很难想像能从一个这么简单的物体
To think that one could create a new world...
创造出一个新世界
...with such a simple little object.
它就像一个种子
It's like a seed.
它只需要水
And all it needs is water.
就像…
Like...
海猴
...Sea-Monkeys.
没错 咪咪
Exactly, Kitty.
就像海猴
Like Sea-Monkeys.
克拉克这几年做了很多心灵之旅
Clark has been doing a little soul-searching for the last couple years.
- 他见了好几位喇嘛 - 是吗？
- He saw Ilamas. - Yeah?
- 嗯 - 回来对你来说很困难吧？
- Yeah. - Must be tough coming back.
- 回来？ - 回来工作
- Coming back? - To work.
嗯
Yeah.
变化了很多
Well, you know, things change.
我是说 事物当然会变化
I mean, of course things change...
但有时候一些你觉得不会变的也变了
...but sometimes things that you didn't think would change could change.
例如露意丝
Take Lois.
没想到像她这样的女人会安定下来
A woman like her, I never thought she'd settle down.
如果你问我… 因为她永远不会说这个
You know, if you ask me... Because she'll never tell you this...
但如果你问我 她还在爱着"那个人"
...but if you ask me, she's still in love with you-know-who.
原本的太空梭在发射时
The original space shuttle generated 7.5 million pounds of thrust...
会产生750万磅的推动力
...just in the initial launch phase.
不过我们把它装载在波音777的背上时…
But, by piggybacking on this Boeing 777... Yes?
如果这次的发射真如你说的那么重要
If this launch is as pivotal as you claim...
为什么只有一家媒体来采访这个消息
...why is it being covered by one news network?
我们何不把这问题留到发射后的记者会
Why don't we save those questions for the post-launch briefing.
可以吗 莲恩小姐？
How about that, Miss Lane?
当我们到达四万尺时
When we hit 40,000 feet, the shuttle will detach, ascend...
太空梭会解放第一组的液态推进器
...and then fire the first of two propellant systems, the liquid fuel boosters.
当我们到达平流层时
When the shuttle reaches the stratosphere...
第二组推进器会被点燃
...the secondary insertion booster will fire...
然后以4g的加速度将我们推入中气层
...propelling the craft at 4gs into the mesosphere.
- 小心 - 我知道
- Careful. - I know.
- 小心 小心 - 我知道
- Careful. Careful. - I know.
哇 真剌激啊 雷克斯
Wow, that's really something, Lex.
再等一下
Wait for it.
哇 真剌激啊 雷克斯
Wow, that's really something, Lex.
剌激度可媲美《飘》了
It's freaking Gone With the Wind.
- 把摄影机关了 - 我还在拍摄啊
- Shut off the camera. - But I'm getting it.
我说把摄影机关了
I said, shut off the damn camera.
我好像弄坏了什么
I think I did something wrong.
不 不是你的错
No. That wasrt you.
1分钟点火倒计时 准备进行梭机分离
Ignition is at T minus one minute and we are prepping for separation.
机长 请开始计时
CDR, start the clock.
3分钟倒计时
Three minutes and counting.
主体信号正常 各部分零件正常
Body signs normal. Crew is looking good.
太空梭仪表稳定
Shuttle readouts are holding steady.
- 我们还是要准备发射 - 明白
- We're still a go for launch. - Roger.
- 休斯敦 收到请回答 - 休斯敦 收到请回答
- Houston, you copy? - Houston, do you copy?
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
电力不稳
Electrical variance.
到底是…
What the...
大家别慌
Please, there's nothing to worry about.
看来我们好像有个小小的停电
It seems that we are experiencing a slight power outage.
- 你做了什么？ - 什么都没做 只是打开了备用电源
- What did you do? - It wasrt me. It just cycled back up.
"创世纪" 和休士顿确认一下
Genesis, radio check from Houston.
他们确认是短暂的停电
There we have it. We were experiencing a power outage.
- 爬升至四万尺 - 收到 四万尺
- Climbing to 40,000 feet. - Roger, 40,000 feet.
他得分了 惊人的快球…
And it's gone! A blazing fastball...
停了吗？
Is that it?
还没呢
I don't think so.
双引擎失效 但是又恢复运转了
Dual engine failure, but they're up and running again.
"创世纪" 很遗憾 我们必须中止这次发射
Genesis, I hate to say this, but it looks like we're gonna have to scrub the launch.
- 中止推进器点火 - 收到 中止推进器点火
- Aborting booster ignition. - Roger. Aborting booster ignition.
推进器没反应 点火还在倒数计时中
Boosters are non-responsive. We're still counting down for ignition.
- 运载机 我们有麻烦了 - 请讲
- Platform, we have a problem. - Go.
看来跳电时什么东西坏了
Looks like something faulted during the power outage.
两组推进器都还在倒数计时中
Both boosters are counting down for ignition.
运载机 还有30秒
Platform, you have 30 seconds.
- 什么？ - 解除连接器
- What? - Release couplings.
我们无法关掉推进器
We can 't shut down boosters.
太空梭可以自行发射然后紧急迫降
We should be able to manage the launch and recover to the emergency field.
倒数23妙
T minus 23 seconds to ignition.
"创世纪" 允进启动紧急疏散程序
Genesis, you're a go for evac procedures.
21 20
Twenty-one, twenty...
Nineteen...
连接器没有反应
Couplings are non-responsive.
- 我们还连在上面 - 17
- We're still attached. - Seventeen.
- 连接器也卡死了 - 15
- Platform, couplings are jammed. - Fifteen.
Fourteen.
不用紧张 这是正常的
Don't be alarmed. It's absolutely normal.
还是解不开 连接器无反应
We're still attached. Couplings are non-responsive.
- 9 8… - 休斯敦 你能从远端解除吗？
- Nine, eight... - Houston, can you do a remote override?
Seven...
- 远端解除无效 - 6 5
- Remote override is unresponsive. - Six, five...
- 重复一遍 远端解除无效 - 4 3…
- I repeat, remote override is unresponsive. -Four, three...
运气好的话还可以听到小声的音爆喔
And if you're lucky, you may hear the faint pop of the sonic boom.
- 休斯敦 点火成功 - 收到
- Houston, we have ignition. - Roger, ignition.
这是蟒蛇21号 太空梭快速远去
This is Python 21, she's pulling away.
飞行控制启动中…
Okay, all flight control is on the...
这不是演习 疏散无关人员
This is not a drill. Clear nonessential personnel.
启动紧急应对方案
Switch to emergency band frequencies.
警告 警告
Warning, warning.
不 不
Oh, no! Oh, no!
谁来帮帮我？
Can I get a little help?
这里是华盛顿UPV电台的即时新闻
This is UPV breaking news. From Washington, Frank Jacobs.
我们刚得到消息
We've just received word...
"创世纪"太空梭在空中遇到问题
...that the inaugural flight of the Genesis space shuttle...
半空中遇到紧急情况
...is experiencing a midair emergency.
新一代"创世纪"发射遭遇问题
A problem with the launch of the new orbital shuttle, Genesis.
消息来源指出创世纪未能和777解开
The reports are telling us the shuttle failed to disengage...
导致二机一起冲向太空
...sending both crafts rocketing towards space.
现在将镜头转回卡纳维尔角… 关注最新动向
We're now going live to Cape Canaveral for the latest update on this story.
吉姆 我们现在只知道
Jim, all we know right now...
777出现故障
...is that the couplings which hold the shuttle to the 777...
机梭未按计划分离
...malfunctioned and did not release as planned.
- 我们还不确定… - 我应该…
- We're uncertain... - I should do...
为何点火程序继续推进器发射
...why the ignition sequence continued and boosters fired.
然而 停电导致很大问题…
However, there's speculation here that the blackout, which...
扶我坐起来
Help me sit up.
火狐1号仍连接在太空梭上 已爬升至42000尺
Mach one. Still tied to the shuttle at 42,000 feet.
- 休斯敦 我们请求支援  - 准备运行故障诊断程序
- Houston, we need some help. Houston! - Running diagnostics check. Stand by.
"入轨推进器"点火5秒倒计时
Insertion booster ignition in five seconds.
警告 警告
Warning, warning.
那到底是什么？
What the hell is that?
有不知名的敌机从北面过来
There's some kind of unidentified bogey coming from the north.
- 了解 - 而且以超快的速度
- Roger that. - And it's coming in fast.
紧急情况
Declaring an emergency.
超速 超速
Overspeed, overspeed.
高度…
Altitude...
看到了吗？
Do you see that?
上升 上升
Fly up, fly up.
大家都没事吧
Is everyone all right?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
那么我希望大家不要因此次事件 而害怕飞行
Well, I hope this experience hasn't put any of you off flying.
因为数据上来说 飞行还是最安全的
Statistically speaking, it's still the safest way to travel.
超人 超人 超人
Superman! Superman! Superman!
超人
Superman!
大家听好了
Okay, everybody, listen up.
我要知道所有的事情
I wanna know it all, everything.
欧森 我要他的照片占满所有版面
Olsen, I wanna see photos of him everywhere.
不 我要看到他的"独家"照片
No, I want the photos.
体育版 他们如何把飞机运出场外？
Sports, how are they gonna get that plane out of the stadium?
旅游版 他之前去哪了？ 渡假吗？ 在哪里？
Travel, where did he go? Was he on vacation? If so, where?
八卦版 他有新恋情吗？
Gossip, has he met somebody?
时尚版 他穿的超人服是新的吗？
Fashion, is that a new suit?
健康版 他增重了吗？ 他都吃些什么？
Health, has he gained weight? What's he been eating?
商务版 这对股市有什么影响？ 短期或长期
Business, how is this gonna affect the stock market? Long-term, short-term.
政治版 他还是正义和事实的代表吗 生活版
Politics, does he still stand for truth, justice, all that stuff? Lifestyle:
"超人归来"
"Superman Returns."
快去吧
Come on.
吉伯 "灾难性"这个字里有几个"F"
Gil, how many F's in "catastrophic"?
一个都没有 如何使用？
None. What's the usage?
神秘的电磁波让所有的电子产品及 便携设备失效
"This mysterious electromagnetic pulse knocked out portable devices...
导致一连串灾难性的…
...and entire power grids, causing a catastrophic event during..."
- 露意丝  - 是
- Lois! - Yes.
到我办公室来
In my office.
大家也都听好了
This goes for everyone.
这次的新闻不是大停电 而是超人
The story isn't the blackout, it's Superman!
主编 电磁波事件才是真正的新闻
The story is the EMP, chief.
东岸所有的电子仪器都在瞬间失效
Every electronic device on the East Coast goes dark.
- 首先 你没事吧 - 没事 谢谢
- First, are you okay? - Yes, thank you.
露意丝 好卖的报纸有三要素： 惨案 性 还有超人
Lois, three things sell papers: Tragedy, sex and Superman.
人们对灾难已快失去兴趣了 你对性爱又一窍不通
People are sick of tragedy, we know you can't write won'th a damn about sex.
所以剩下来的只剩超人了
That means one thing. That one thing is Superman. And you know it, Lois.
露意丝？
Lois?
- 你没事吧 - 嗯
- Are you all right? You sure? - Yeah.
- 我没事 - 谢天谢地
- Yeah, I'm fine. - Thank God.
- 杰森呢？ - 他不是跟你在一起吗？
- Where's Jason? - I don 't know. Isn 't he with you?
- 没有 - 他人呢？
- No. - Well, where is he?
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是克拉克·肯特 我在你还没出生时就和你妈妈是朋友了
I'm Clark Kent, an old friend of your mom's from before you were born.
是吗？ 她从来没提过你
Really? She never mentioned you.
真的吗？ 从没？
Really? Never?
- 从没 - 杰森
- No. - Jason.
- 你在这里做什么 宝贝？ - 爸爸的办公室好无聊
- What are you doing here, honey? - Daddy's office is boring.
爸爸的办公室好无聊？
Daddy's office is boring?
克拉克 嗨 欢迎回来
Clark, hey! Welcome back.
- 你已经见过我儿子了 - 对啊 我们正在聊天
- I see you've already met the munchkin. - Yeah, we were just talking...
- 你吃维生素了吗 点眼药了吗？ - 吃了 点了
- Did you take vitamins? Eye drops? - Yes. Yes.
- 气喘药呢？ 波利拜弗呢？ - 都吃了 妈妈
- Albuterol? Poly-Vi-Flor? - Yes. Yes, Mom.
乖孩子 他现在身体不太好 但他长大以后…
Good boy. He's a little fragile, but he's gonna grow up...
一定会长得跟他爸爸一样高大强壮 是吧
...to be big and strong like his dad, won't you?
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Yes? - Yes.
我看见你在那飞机…
Oh, I saw you on the...
哦 那没什么
Oh, yeah. That was nothing.
- 你的订书机能借我吗？ - 当然
- Hey, can I borrow your stapler? - Oh, yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
恭喜你得到普利兹奖 真不可思议
Congratulations on the Pulitzer. That's incredible.
对呀 难以相信
Yeah. Can you believe it? It's...
对了 你的旅行如何？
So I wanna hear all about your trip.
你去了哪里？ 看到什么？ 认识了什么人吗？
Where did you go? What did you see? Meet anyone special?
太多了 我不知从何说起
Well, there's so much. Where to begin?
那小子呢？ 嘿 小子
Where's the little guy? Hey, kiddo.
- 你好吗？ - 很好
- How are you? - Good.
你能不能向你的叔叔拉点亲戚关系
Can you work some magic to get your uncle...
让他不要一直为难我这篇报导？
...to stop giving me such a hard time on this article?
- 行吗？ - 又一次？
- Please? - Again?
- 又一次 - 没问题
- Again. - You got it.
- 你好吗 孩子？ - 好
- How are you, kiddo? - Good.
哦 这是克拉克
Oh, this is Clark.
- 克拉克 理查；理查 克拉克 - 理查·怀特
- Clark, Richard. Richard, Clark. - Richard White.
嗨
Hi.
理查是这里的副编辑 他一手拯救了我们的国际版
Richard's an assistant editor here who's basically saved our International section.
他也是个飞行员 喜欢看恐怖电影
He's also a pilot and he loves horror movies.
克拉克是…
Clark is...
他就是克拉克
Well, he's Clark.
真高兴终于见到你 我听说了很多你的事
Well, it's great to finally meet you. I've heard so much.
- 是吗？ - 是啊 吉米这小子一直说到你
- Oh, you have? - Yeah, Jimmy won't shut up about you.
- 该走了 - 去哪？
- Gotta run. - Where?
你听到啦 派瑞说超人回来了 而我是唯一能…
You heard Perry. Supermars back, and he thinks I'm the only one equipped to...
能什么？
To what?
- 不知道 - 那就别理他
- I don't know, you know. - So don't listen to him.
我是不理啊 我现在要去发电厂调查停电
I'm not. Going to the power plant to check out the blackout.
好吧
Okay.
- 妈妈再见 - 再见
- Bye, Mom. - Bye.
- 再见 露意丝 - 她走了
- Bye, Lois. - And she's gone.
不管我们有多亲近 对我来说那女人一直是个谜
No matter how close we are, that woman will always be a mystery.
需要什么的话 我的办公室在那里
If you need anything, I'm right over there.
很高兴见到你
Nice to finally meet you.
你要去哪？ 去公园吗？
Where do you wanna go? Wanna go to the park?
∮ 整个世界 在他手中 ∮
∮ And he's got the whole world In his hands. ∮
∮ 整个世界... ∮
∮ He's got the whole world... ∮
∮ 整个世界 在他手中 ∮
∮ And he's got the whole world in his hands. ∮
(超人回来啦)
他蛮可爱的嘛
Oh, he's cute.
(陨石碎片和宝石 现于大都会自然科学博物馆展览中)
碰上麻烦吗？
Run into trouble?
- 你应该问对方 - 我们接下来做什么？
- Should see the other guy. - What are we gonna do?
你们把它改造后装在船尾
Modify it, attach it to the stern.
我不管说明书是不是俄文写成的
I don't care if the instructions are Russian.
- 露意丝 - 克拉克
- Lois? - Hey, Clark.
回来工作的感觉怎样？
How does it feel to be back at work?
蛮不错呀 就像骑脚踏车吧
Pretty good. You know, kind of like riding a bike, I guess.
- 脚踏车？ - 对呀 嗯…
- A bike? - Yeah, you know...
算了
Never mind.
我在想…
But I was wondering...
我回来后我们还没有聚在一起聊聊
...since I've gotten back, we haven't really had a chance to catch up.
如果你不介意的话 我们可以去吃个饭
I thought maybe, if you'd like, we could go grab some food...
- 我可以问你一件事吗？ - 当然
- Hey, can I ask you something? - Sure.
你认识了某人 你们感觉像是两个不同世界的人
Have you ever met someone and it's like you're from different worlds...
但你们之间却燃起了强烈的爱情火花
...but you shared such a connection
你知道你们是注定要在一起的
you knew you were destined to be together?
但他突然间就离开了
Then he just takes off without explaining why...
连一点解释或一句再见都没说
...or without even saying goodbye?
蛮低级的吧
Sounds cheesy, I know.
- 不过 也许… - 计程车
- Well, maybe... - Taxi!
说再见对他来说太困难了
...it was hard to say goodbye because he had to go...
也许他想说 但说不出口
...and he wanted to say goodbye, but maybe it was too difficult for him.
困难？ 有什么好困难的 "再见"很简单啊
Difficult? What's so difficult about it? "Goodbye." It's easy.
说再见有什么困难？
What's so hard about saying goodbye?
我们到底在说谁呀？
Who are we talking about?
没说谁 当我没说过吧
Nobody, just forget I said anything.
计程车 嘿
Taxi! Hey!
计程车
Taxi!
哇 谢谢
Wow, thanks.
河滨路312号 谢谢
312 Riverside Drive, please.
晚安 克拉克
Good night, Clark.
超人
Superman!
我要蛋卷
I want egg rolls.
没办法 小子 你只能吃鸡块和雪豆
Nice try, kiddo. Only steamed chicken and snow peas for you.
你明知他会过敏为何还要叫中餐外卖？
Why do we order Chinese if he's allergic?
因为他喜欢雪豆
Because he loves the peas...
与微机生物制成的奶昔比起来 我们也比较喜欢吃蛋卷吧
...and I think we all prefer egg rolls over macrobiotic shakes.
那倒也是
It's a good point.
我发现你最近举动怪怪的
So I noticed you've been acting a little different lately.
是吗？
Have I?
露意丝 你写的那篇文章
You know, Lois, that article that you wrote.
为何这世界不需要超人？
"Why the World Doesrt Need Superman"?
不不不 另一篇 在我们认识前写的
No, no, no. No, the other one, from years ago, before we met.
哪一篇啊 我写了好多篇 我就是他的新闻发言人
Which article? I wrote dozens about him. I was practically his press agent.
我和超人共渡良宵
"I Spent the Night With Superman."
理查 算了
Richard, come on.
那只不过是文章的标题
It was the title of an interview.
而且那还是你叔叔派瑞的主意
Plus, it was your Uncle Perry's idea.
- 我知道 我知道 没关系 - 理查
- No, I know, I know. It's okay, it's okay. - Richard.
那是很久以前的事了
It was a long time ago.
你那时爱着他吗？
Were you in love with him?
他是超人呀 所有人都爱他
He was Superman. Everyone was in love with him.
那你呢？
But were you?
不爱
No.
露意丝 我不该提这个的
Lois, I shouldn 't have brought it up.
虽然你被当成人类抚养长大
Even though you've been raised as a human being...
你毕竟不是人类
...you are not one of them.
他们可以成为也渴望成为伟大的人 凯尔
They can be a great people, Kal-EI. They wish to be.
他们缺少的是一道照亮道路的光
They only lack the light to show the way.
因为这个原因
For this reason above all, their capacity for good...
我把你 我唯一的儿子
...I have sent them you...
给了他们
...my only son.
把货装上去
Load them up.
妈的…
Holy sh...
注意 大都会博物馆
Attention, the Metropolis Museum of Natural History...
将在十分钟后关门
...will be closing in 10 minutes. We hope that you've...
我们再过十分钟就关了
Sir, we're closing in 10 minutes.
我们只需要五分钟
We only need five.
你们该走了 博物馆关门了 谢谢
You're done, the museum's closed. Thank you.
你还好吧 小姐？
Are you all right, miss?
- 我的心脏… - 什么？
- My heart. L... l... - I'm sorry?
我有心悸 还有心杂音
I have a palpitation, a heart palpitation. And a murmur.
请你带我去医院
Please, take me to the hospital.
带我去医院
Take me to the hospital.
抓紧了
Just hold on tight.
搞定
Bingo.
(1978年  亚的斯亚贝巴L9铁矿陨石)
(硼硅酸锂纳 氢氧化物以及氟化物  埃塞俄比亚·亚的斯亚贝巴)
- 到了 女士 - 我的心脏
- There you are, ma'am. - My heart.
我的心悸停止了 你做了什么？
My palpitations, they're gone. What did you do?
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything.
叫我凯瑟琳
Call me Katherine.
凯瑟琳 很高兴你没事了
Katherine. I'm glad you're feeling better.
- 你还得去很多地方 救很多人？ - 对
- You have places to go, people to save? - Yes.
你要不要一起喝杯咖啡…
Would you like to get a cup of coffee sometime?
- 我知道这太直接了点 酒怎么样？ - 晚安 凯瑟琳
- I know that's forward. Or a drink? - Good night.
晚安
Good night.
好像每个频道都是这个
It's like this on every channel.
他晚上10:55出现在马尼拉 然后又…
He was in Manila at 10:55 p.m. And then spotted...
- 肯特 主编在等你 - 谢谢
- Hey, Kent, chief wants to see you. - Oh, thanks.
熟食店抢劫的保安录像证明
But as this security footage from a simple deli robbery proves...
恰好是超人
...there's really no feat too big or too small for the Man of Steel.
洪水般的报道淹没了休斯敦和纽约
Reports are flooding in from Metropolis, Houston, Gotham and as far...
卫星对于追踪他最没用
Satellites have proven most ineffective at tracking him.
他移动速度接近光速
He might literally be moving near the speed of light.
- 我们的地图上到处是光点 - 肯特
- Our map is illuminated with sightings... - Kent!
- 主编在等你 - 在每个大陆上 让市民…
- The chief is waiting. - on every continent, giving citizens...
这些照片很有象征性 而且是一个十二岁的小孩用手机拍的
These are iconic, and they were taken by a 12-year-old with a camera phone.
- 你拍到些什么 欧森？ - 我拍到这些
- What do you got, Olsen? - I got those.
- 看天空的部分 主编 - 那是鸟
- Look, in the sky, chief. - It's a bird.
- 那是飞机 - 不 看 那是…
- It's a plane. - No, look, it's...
你们在找我吗？
You wanted to see me?
肯特 进来坐下
Yeah, Kent, come on in. Sit down.
我想讨论一下策略问题
I wanna talk a little strategy. Okay.
首先 露意丝 我不懂你为何
First off, Lois, I don't understand what you're doing...
- 紧追着停电的报导不放 - 那不是普通的停电
- sneaking around covering the blackout. - It wasrt just a blackout.
手机、传呼机、汽车、飞机…
Cell phones, pagers, automobiles, airplane...
其它的报社都至少有一位女记者
Every other paper in town has got a female reporter...
漂亮的女记者在屋顶做超人的报导
...a good-Iooking female reporter, stashed on the roof covering Superman.
而你是唯一和超人有一段历史的
And you two are the ones with history.
我已经做过超人了
Chief, I've done Superman.
报道他 你们明白什么意思
Covered him. You know what I mean.
没错 所以你是个专家 你要继续报导他
Yeah, that makes you an expert. Do him again.
可是还有很多其它的事情可报啊
There are a dozen other stories out there.
是吗？ 举个例子
Yeah? Name one.
昨天博物馆的抢劫
Well, there was a museum robbery last night.
连超人也顾不及那件案子 当时忙着救这个骚货呢
Even Superman missed that one. He was too busy saving this hooker.
你们为什么不去追查雷克斯·路瑟的下落？
Why don't you guys track down Lex Luthor?
自从他第五次上诉后就没人再看见过他
Well, no one's seen him since his fifth appeal.
而且他跟超人间有数不清的过节
He's got more history with Superman than anyone.
也许他知道些什么
Maybe he's got something to say.
- 路瑟是旧闻了 - 不 我觉得这主意不错
- Luthor's yesterday's news. - No, I like that idea.
派瑞 雷克斯·路瑟是个职业惯犯 他还差点杀死过超人
Perry, Lex Luthor is a career criminal who nearly killed him, for God's sakes.
吉米 雷克斯路瑟怎么被释放的？
Jimmy, how did Lex Luthor get out of prison?
上诉法庭传超人做证 结果他没出庭
Well, the appeals court called Superman as a witness and he wasrt around.
你想超人知道的话会不会气死？
How much do you think that pisses off Superman?
- 把他交给别人吧 - 很生气
- Give him to someone else. - A lot.
- 很生气 - 让波莉去做吧
- A lot. - Polly. Give him to Polly.
露意丝 超人
Lois, Superman.
- 那大停电怎么办？ - 肯特 你做大停电
- What about the blackout? - Kent, blackout.
太好了 真谢谢你 主编
Great. Thanks, chief.
露意丝 对不起 我不想这会破坏我们的关系
Lois, I'm sorry. I'd hate if this damaged our relationship.
关系？
Relationship?
- 对 - 嗨 妈妈
- Yeah. - Hi, Mommy.
- 你好啊 - 大家好
- Hi, you. - Hey, guys.
他科学拿到了A 体操得了D 至少我们做对了一些
He got an A in science, but a D in gym, so we're doing something right.
- 至少我们之中有一个是对的 - 什么？
- Yeah, at least one of us is. - What?
派瑞 他又把超人推给我了
It's Perry. He just shoved Superman back into my life.
亲爱的 我相信你能找到办法采访超人
Well, honey, I'm sure you can find a way to interview Superman...
却又不让他再走进你的生活的
...without bringing him back into your life.
无可否认的 超人回来了
There's really no way around it, folks. Superman is back in all of our lives.
我们在悉尼下城
We're coming to you from Sydney...
在商业区的屋顶上为您做实况转播
...where people have gathered on these rooftops to scour the sky...
不如这样吧 我们赶夜工 叫外卖来吃
Okay, how about this? We'll stay late. We'll get dinner.
我来帮你写超人的报导 你跟克拉克一起写大停电
I'll help with Superman, and you and Clark can work on the blackout together.
- 你觉得如何 克拉克？ - 帅呆了
- Is that all right with you, Clark? - Swell.
我应该是假装煞车失灵
I was gonna pretend the brakes were out.
假装耶 我们之前讨论过的
Pretend. Like we talked about.
你不必真的把煞车线剪断吧
You didn't actually have to cut them!
我当然需要
Of course I did.
男人一向都知道当女人在装假 尤其是超人
A man can always tell when a woman is pretending, especially Superman.
你拿到你的石头了吗？
So did you get your rock?
拿到了
I did.
全国海岸警卫队提醒小型船只
U.S. Coast Guard issuing a small-craft advisory for the Metropolis ocean area.
风力很大
High-wind advisory is in effect...
潮汐越来越危险
...ocean currents and tides becoming increasingly dangerous.
所有警报持续到今晚
All warnings lasting until later this evening.
安全警报
Security, security.
全国海岸警卫队提醒东北海域小型船只
This is U.S. Coast Guard issuing a small-craft advisory for northeast seas.
风速达50英里 今早有巨浪
Winds reaching 50 miles per hour, high tides in the morning.
浪高20至30尺
Waves reaching 20 to 30 feet.
此警告保留4小时
This warning is in effect for all small crafts for the next four hours.
奇怪 如果这些时间正确
Weird. If these times are right...
那大停电是从一个中心点开始扩散的
...the blackout spread from a specific origin point.
从哪里？
Where?
我还不确定
I'm not sure yet.
他的超级听力是一次听到一个声音 还是听到很多声音？
With the super-hearing, does he hear each sound by itself or everything at once?
都可以
Both.
- 他比我想像中高多了 - 六尺四
- He's certainly taller than I thought. - 6'4".
我真羡慕他能看穿任何东西 那一定很好玩
I love that he can see through anything. I'd have fun with that.
除了铅以外
Anything but lead.
- 我想他一定… - 225磅
- I bet he's... - 225 pounds...
速度快于一颗子弹
...faster than a speeding bullet...
从太阳汲取能量 除了氪星石外不怕任何东西
...draws his power from the sun, invulnerable to anything but kryptonite...
- 从不说谎 - 氪星石？
- and he never lies. - Kryptonite?
他的母星碎片 含有高量幅射
Radioactive pieces of his home world.
那可以杀死他
It's deadly. To him.
露意丝 你说克拉克有多高
Lois, how tall would you say Clark is?
六尺三、四
About 6'3", 6'4".
200-215磅？
About 200, 215 pounds?
吉米 杰森 我们去帮这些无畏的记者们
Jimmy, Jason, let's go get these intrepid reporters
买些晚餐让他们能继续奋斗下去吧
something to keep them going.
- 要玉米煎饼  - 过来
- Burritos! - Come here, canead.
这边来 除了玉米煎饼还有什么？
We're going this way. Do they have anything other than burritos?
我想他们有炸鸡块和肉夹饼
I think they have fries and burgers.
你找到地方住了吗？
So have you found a place to live yet?
我还在找
No. I'm still looking.
露意丝 我正好想问你…
You know, Lois, I wanted to ask you about that artic...
嘿 我正想下楼透透气 真是的
Hey, I'm gonna run downstairs for some fresh air. Great!
谢谢
Thanks.
- 等我回来我们再聊吧 - 好吧
- Let's talk when I get back. - Sure.
你实在不该吸烟的 莲恩小姐
You know, you really shouldn't smoke, Miss Lane.
- 不好意思 我不是有意吓你 - 我没事 真的
- Sorry. Didrt mean to startle you. - I'm fine. Really.
我只是没想到会看到你
I just wasrt expecting you.
当时机上太多媒体
With all the press on the plane...
那种情况下不太好说话
...I wasrt sure it was the best time for us to talk.
现在没有媒体了 除了我以外
Well, there's no press around now. Except for me, of course.
我回来后 大家都有很多问题
I know people are asking questions now that I'm back.
我也有义务回答他们
I think it's only fair that I answer those people.
所以…你是来接受采访的？
So you're here for an interview?
好吧
Okay, then.
- 我把它放哪去了 - 你右边口袋
- Where did I put that thing? - Right pocket.
我们由最大的问题开始吧
Let's start with the big question.
- 你跑哪去了？ - 氪星
- Where'd you go? - To Krypton.
你说过它早就被毁灭掉了
But you told me it was destroyed. Ages ago.
我是说过
It was.
但有一些太空人以为 他们找到星球的残骸时
But when astronomers thought they found it...
我必须亲自去确认一下
...I had to see for myself.
现在你回来了 大家看起来也很高兴
Well, you're back, and everyone seems to be pretty happy about it.
但不是所有人
Not everyone.
- 我读过那篇文章 露意丝 - 很多人都读过
- I read the article, Lois. - So did a lot of people.
明天他们授予我普利兹奖
Tomorrow they're giving me the Pulitzer...
你为什么要写那篇文章？
Why did you write it?
你怎么可以就这样离开我们？
How could you leave us like that?
我痛过后看开了 大家都看开了
I moved on. So did the rest of us.
所以我才写这篇文章
That's why I wrote it.
这个世界不需要救世主
The world doesn't need a savior.
我也不需要
And neither do I.
露意丝
Lois.
你能跟我来吗？
Will you come with me?
为什么？
Why?
我想让你看一些东西
There's something I wanna show you.
来吧
Please.
我不能去太久
I can't be gone long.
不会太久的
You won't be.
克拉克说你不告而别…
Clark said the reason you left without saying goodbye...
是因为道别对你来说太痛苦了
...is because it was too unbearable for you.
我觉得那根本就是胡说
Personally, I think that's a load of crap.
- 克拉克？ - 是我公司的同事
- Clark? - He's just a guy I work with.
也许克拉克说的没错
Maybe Clark's right.
你知道 我的…
You know, my...
理查…是个飞行员 他常常带我一起去飞行
Richard, he's a pilot. He takes me up all the time.
不是这样的飞行
Not like this.
我忘记你身体有多温暖了
I forgot how warm you were.
仔细听
Listen.
你听到了什么？
What do you hear?
什么都没有
Nothing.
我全听到了
I hear everything.
你写道世界不需要救世主
You wrote that the world doesn't need a savior...
可是每天我都听到人们的呼救
...but every day I hear people crying for one.
对不起我当时离开你 露意丝
I'm sorry I left you, Lois.
我现在带你回去
I'll take you back now.
理查是个好人
Richard's a good man.
而且你又离开那么久
And you've been gone a long time.
我知道
I know.
我…
L...
我还会看到你吗？
So will I see you around?
我一直都在
I'm always around.
晚安 露意丝
Good night, Lois.
我买了牛肉回来 你要用豆腐皮还是蔬菜皮？
We're having beef, honey. Do you want the tofu wrap or the veggie wrap?
你还好吗？
You all right?
你去哪了？
Where have you been?
我…刚才上屋顶去透透气
I was up on the roof, getting some air.
说实话喔
Tell the truth now.
你去抽烟吗？
Were you smoking?
不是
No.
真的？
Is this real?
- 你怎么找到他的？ - 是他找到我
- Where'd you find him? - He found me.
太棒了 我真等不及要读这篇报导
Oh, this is great. I can't wait to read it.
怀特先生 有关大停电…
So, Mr. White, about the blackout...
露意丝 今晚是你人生中最重要的夜晚
Lois, this is the biggest night of your life.
你选好服装了吗 很高贵的服装吗
Have you picked out a dress? Something snazzy?
我只是觉得以这篇文章获奖很奇怪
It just feels a little weird winning for that article.
- 不大对劲 - 哪不对劲？
- It just doesn't seem right. - What doesn't seem right?
这篇文章说世界不需要超人
Winning an award for an article called "Why the World Doesrt Need Superman."
可是所有的报纸上写的正好是相反
When, according to this newspaper, they do.
露意丝 普利兹奖就像奥斯卡奖
Lois, Pulitzer Prizes are like Academy Awards.
没人会记得你以什么作品得奖的 他们只会记得你得过奖
Nobody remembers what you got one for. It's just that you got one.
- 但… - 今晚是属于你的 好好享受吧
- But... - This is your night. You enjoy it.
肯特会写大停电的
I'm sure Kent's on the blackout.
请接水电部
Department of Water and Power, please.
7782 好的
7782, great.
大都会工共设施部门
Metropolis Public Works.
嗨 史帝芬 我是星球日报的露意丝莲恩
Hi, Stephen, Lois Lane from the Daily Planet. Blackout?
大停电？ 我只是想问一下电力分布图
I just need a little info on a few outstanding power grids.
是的 我这里有
Yeah, I do have it here, actually.
所以住宅区在12:36时停电
So the uptown grid went dark at 12:36
商住宅区在那之前十秒停电
and midtown 10 seconds before.
哪一区是最先停的？
Which grid was hit first?
在下林的附近
It just reads Vanderwon'th.
- 河的对岸吗？ - 春木街6号
- Across the river? - 6 Springwood Drive.
春木街6号 那是个商业还是住宅？
6 Springwood Drive. A residence or a business?
- 住宅 - 你确定吗？ 再之前就没有停电了？
- Residence. - Sure? Nothing before that?
- 我确定 - 非常感谢
- That's all it shows. - Thank you very much.
糟糕 杰森
Oh, Jason.
- 你妈妈来了 - 你迟到了 妈咪
- There's your mom, Jason. - You're late, Mommy.
我们在哪里？ 这是普莉兹奖会场吗？
Where are we? Is this the Pulitzer?
不是 我只是要问这家人一些问题 马上就好了
Nope. I've just gotta ask these people a few questions and then we can go.
(来电： 星球日报)
我可以待在车子里吗？
Can I stay in the car?
不行 亲爱的
No, honey.
- 我们这样算擅自闯入吗？ - 不算…算
- Are we trespassing? - No. Yes.
有人在吗？
Hello?
(来电： 理查 未接)
有人在吗？
Hello?
我喜欢那顶
I like the curly one.
我们走 我们不该进来的
Let's go. This was a bad idea.
雷克斯·路瑟
Lex Luthor.
露意丝·莲恩？
Lois Lane?
你秃头
You're bald.
你叫什么名字？
And what is your name?
我不可以跟陌生人讲话
I'm not supposed to talk to strangers.
- 真可爱 又聪明 - 谢谢
- Cute kid, and smart. - Thanks.
可是我们可不是陌生人喔 这应该可说是一个小重逢吧
We're not really strangers, are we? This is kind of a little reunion.
我是你的仰慕者
Heck, I'm a fan.
我喜欢你的作品
I love your writing...
- 还有你的衣服 - 我喜欢你的船
- and your dress. - I love your boat.
你怎么弄来的？ 是不是又去骗哪个寡妇的钱？
How'd you get it? Swindle some widow out of her money?
呵呵 真幽默 你不是得了普莉兹奖吗？
That's funny. Didrt you win the Pulitzer Prize...
题目是我最喜欢的"为什么这世界不需要超人"
...for my favorite article of all time, " Why the World Doesrt Need Superman"?
你的双重无期徒刑不是还有好几年牢要坐吗
Didrt you have a few more years to go on that double life sentence?
对呀 我该谢谢超人
Yes, well, we can thank the Man of Steel for that.
虽然他很会抓坏人
I mean, he's really good at swooping in and catching the bad guys...
可是他对小事就不太内行
...but he's not so hot at the little things, like Miranda rights...
例如米兰达权利 正当法律程序 准时出庭作证等等
...due process, making your court date.
你是不是跟大停电事件有关？
Did you have anything to do with the blackout?
你想要采访我吗 莲恩小姐？
Are you fishing for an interview, Miss Lane?
你也好一阵子没出现在头版了
It's been a while since you've been a headline.
也许人们应该再听听你的名字了
Maybe it's time people knew your name again.
不如我们把船折返回港 把我儿子送回家
How about we turn this boat around, call a cab for my son...
你想对我怎样都可以
...and then you can do whatever you want with me.
我不会把船折回去的 莲恩小姐
No, I don't think we'll be turning around, Miss Lane...
所以我们有些时间可以闲聊
...which means that we do have some time to kill.
来个采访怎么样啊？
How about that interview?
是的 有任何消息请打给我 谢谢
Yeah, just call me if you hear anything. Okay. Thank you.
学校说什么？
So, what did the school say?
她三点十五分就接走杰森了
She picked him up at 3: 15.
- 嗨 我听说露意丝的事了 - 进来 克拉克 进来
- Hi, I heard about Lois. - Yes, come in, Clark, come in.
- 有什么我可以做的吗？ - 你是记者
- Is there anything I can do? - Yeah, you're a reporter.
- 帮理查把她找出来 - 我去看她的电脑
- Help Richard track her down. - I'll check her computer.
不好意思 克拉克
Excuse me, Clark.
你对水晶知道多少？
What do you know about crystals?
用水晶做的吊灯很漂亮
They make great chandeliers.
这块水晶看起来也许不起眼
This crystal may seem unremarkable,
不过我们那位穿紧身衣的朋友把它拿来
but so is the seed of a redwood tree.
建造他的北极渡假屋
It's how our mutual friend in tights made his Arctic getaway spot.
还蛮可爱的 但对我来说太小了
Cute. It's a little small for my taste.
你想建一座岛？
You're building an island?
你要往更大的方面想 莲恩小姐
You're not seeing the big picture here, Miss Lane.
我帮你把它放大吧
Let me enlarge it for you.
不只是一座岛 是一整个新大陆
Not just an island, an entirely new continent.
从虚无制造出的新大陆
An extinct world, reborn on our own.
为什么？
Why?
土地 莲恩小姐
Land, Miss Lane.
咪咪 我父亲以前常对我说什么？
I mean... Kitty, what did my father used to say to me?
你头发越来越稀疏了？
"You're losing your hair"?
- 在那之前 - 滚出去？
- Before that. - "Get out"?
他说 钱可以印…
He said, " You can print money...
钻石可以制造 人类随手抓就一把
...manufacture diamonds, and people are a dime a dozen...
可是土地…我们永远需要土地
...but they'll always need land."
土地是我们唯一无法制造出来的东西
It's the one thing they're not making any more of.
可是美国…
But the United States...
美国会沉到海底
Will be underwater.
这是很简单的物理学 莲恩小姐
It's simple physics, Miss Lane.
两件物体不能同时占据同一个空间
Two objects cannot occupy the same space at the same time.
世界上其它人难道就会让你为所欲为吗？
And the rest of the world will just let you keep it?
- 他们会… - 他们会…
- They'Il... - They'II...
怎样？
...what?
我将拥有…
I'll have advanced alien technology...
比地球先进数千年的外星科技
...thousands of years beyond what anyone could throw at me.
要打就来吧
Bring it on!
最后…
And eventually...
世界上的人会来求我
...the rest of the world will be begging me...
给他们一块高科技的海滨土地
...for a piece of high-tech beachfront property.
事实上 他们会花大钱来跟我买
In fact, they'll pay through the nose for it.
可是数百万人会因此而死呀
But millions of people will die.
数十亿  媒体又一次低估了我
Billions! Once again, the press underestimates me.
这可登上头版新闻了吧
This is front-page news.
说吧 让我听你说一次 一次就好
Come on, let me hear you say it just once.
- 你是个疯子 - 不对 不是这句 另一句
- You're insane. - No! Not that. No, the other thing.
我知道你已经快脱口而出了 让我听吧 一次就好
It's dangling off the tip of your tongue. Let me hear it just once, please?
- 超人绝不会让你… - 错
- Superman will never... - Wrong!
那是什么？
What is that?
你应该知道这是什么
I think you know exactly what this is.
智力战胜武力 莲恩小姐
Mind over muscle, Miss Lane.
智力
Mind...
这小孩的父亲是谁？
Who is that boy's father?
理查
Richard.
路瑟先生 我们已经接近目的座标了
Mr. Luthor, we're approaching the coordinates.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
是的 北纬40度西经73度
Yes, sir. Latitude 40 degrees north, longitude 73 degrees west.
别让他们离开这房间
Don't let them leave this room.
咪咪 跟我来 你不会想错过这个的
Kitty, come with me. You're not gonna want to miss this.
- 可恶 - 怎么了？
- Damn it. - What?
她设了密码
She has a password.
杰森
"Jason."
理查
"Richard."
试试"超人"
Try "Superman."
"超人" 太棒了
"Superman." Great.
别碰它
Don't touch that, honey.
你去弹弹琴吧
Why don't you go play the piano.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
雷克斯 这不像模型火车呀
Lex, this isn't like the train set.
我知道
I know.
快点 快点
Come on, come on.
快点
Come on.
- 宝贝 你还好吗 - 还好
- Honey, are you okay? - Yeah.
- 没受伤吧？ - 没有
- Are you hurt? - I'm fine.
开门 快开门
Open this door! Open it!
你能帮妈咪开这个门吗？
Could you help Mommy open the door?
对不起
I'm sorry.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
会没事的
Okay? It's gonna be okay.
楼下出了点小问题了
We had a little problem downstairs.
布鲁斯死了
Brutus is dead.
他被钢琴撞死的
He got hit with the piano.
那小孩呢？
Where's the boy?
跟妈妈一起被关在食品储藏室
With the mother, locked up in the pantry.
是时间了 我们走
Oh, it's time for us to go.
我相机出故障了
My camera's not working.
手机也不行了
And my phone's not working.
- 我没事 - 真奇怪
- Okay, I'm good. - That was weird.
(40N 73W 救命)
伙计们 从传真过来的
Hey, guys. This just came through the fax.
这是露意丝的笔迹 我不会认错的
It's Lois' handwriting, I'd recognize it anywhere.
我只是不知道这些号码是什么
I just... No idea what the numbers mean.
- 那是坐标 - 坐标
- They're coordinates. - Coordinates.
这就在出海不远处
That's just off the coast.
吉米 告诉派瑞我把水上飞机开走了
Jimmy, tell Perry I'm taking the seaplane.
还有 继续试她的手机
Keep trying her cell.
这是什么？ 乐透号码？
What are these, lottery numbers?
我想他们是座标 主编
I think they're coordinates, chief.
主编…
Chief...
快点 走啊
Come on! Move it!
主编
Chief!
凯撒大帝的鬼魂
Great Caesar's ghost.
- 爸爸 - 天啊
- Daddy. - Oh, my God.
你怎么来的？
How did you get here?
飞来的
I flew.
小心
Look out!
妈妈
Mom!
妈妈 妈妈
Mom! Mom!
杰森 过来 杰森
Jason, come here! Jason!
过来 小心头 过来
Come here! Watch your head! Come here!
妈妈 妈妈
Mommy! Mom!
杰森
Jason!
杰森 坚持住
Jason, hold on!
- 拉住他了吗？ - 拉住了
- Have you got him? - I got him! Go!
坚持住 坚持住
Hold on! Hold on!
- 妈妈  - 把他给我
- Mommy! - Give him to me!
妈妈
Mommy!
- 妈妈 妈妈  - 加油 杰森 加油
- Mommy! Mommy! - Come on, Jason! Come on!
- 露意丝 露意丝  - 妈妈
- Lois! Lois! - Mommy!
杰森 到我的背上来
Jason, get on my back.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
- 你抓紧他们了吗？ - 是的
- Have you got them? - Yeah.
快上去
Get buckled in!
她会没事的
She'll be fine.
我没办法在这种情况下起飞
I can't take off in this.
- 我可以推你一把 - 谢谢
- I'll point you in the right direction. - Thank you.
有没有看到什么熟悉的东西？
See anything familiar?
我只看到一个老人的变态玩笑
I see an old mars sick joke.
是吗？ 我可是看到我的新公寓
Really? Because I see my new apartment...
有咪咪的地方 还有我朋友的
...and a place for Kitty, one for my friends...
那边那个空间我准备租出去
...and that place over there, I'll rent out.
也许你说的没错 也许这里是冷了点
But, you know, maybe you're right. You know, maybe it is a little cold.
应该怎么形容才好呢？
It's... What's the word I'm searching for? It's a little...
这里有点"外星感"
...alien.
好像少了点人性
It lacks that human touch.
你拿走某样属于我的东西
You have something that belongs to me.
大都会塔台 这是水上飞机 N7241H 号
Metropolis Tower, this is seaplane November-Seven-Two-Four-One-Hotel.
请回答
Do you copy?
大都会塔台 这是水上飞机 N7241H 号
Metropolis Tower, this is seaplane November-Seven-Two-Four-One-Hotel.
请回答
Do you copy? Damn it!
大都会塔台 这是水上飞机 N7241H 号
Metropolis Tower, this is seaplane November-Seven-Two-Four-One-Hotel.
请回答
Do you copy?
露意丝 你没事吧？
Lois! Are you all right?
发生什么事了？
Yeah. What happened?
- 超人救了我们 - 他去哪了？
- Superman. - Where is he?
他回去了
He went back.
- 理查 我们要折回去 - 什么？ 不
- Richard, we have to turn around. - What? No.
- 我们要回去那里  - 我们好不容易才逃出来
- We have to turn around! - We barely made it out of there.
- 你又要叫我飞回去？ - 是的 求求你
- Now you want me to go back? - Yes, please!
他会死的
He'll die.
好吧 抓紧
All right, hold on.
氪星
Kryptonite.
你大概在想 "怎么会"
You're asking yourself, "How?"
爸爸小时候难道没教过自己 要跳跃前先看清楚吗？
Didrt your dad ever teach you to look before you leap?
水晶 它们真不可思议 不是吗？
Crystals. They're amazing, aren't they?
它们将它们身边矿物质的特质变为己有
They inerit the traits of the minerals around them...
就像儿子遗传爸爸的特质一样
...kind of like a son ineriting the traits of his father!
你从我生命中夺走好几年 我现在要报仇
You took away five years of my life, I'm just returning the favor!
我仍是超人
I'm still Superman!
起来
Get up! Come on!
飞吧
Now, fly.
永别了 超人
So long, Superman.
你的领导可影响人类
Your leadership can stir others...
动摇人心
...to their own capacities for moral betterment.
人心仍受巨大谎言的影响
The human heart is still subject to monstrous deceits.
我们的破坏要被制止 在这非常时刻…
Our destruction could have been avoided. At this very moment...
我把你拥入怀中
...I could embrace you in my arms.
你的帮助是无尽的 记住我
Your help would be called for endlessly. Remember me.
即使是那些人类能自己解决的问题
Even for those tasks which human beings could solve themselves.
记住我 凯尔
Remember me, Kal-EI.
记住我
Remember me.
超人在那里
Supermars down there.
- 你确定？ - 是的
- You sure? - Yeah.
- 理查  - 我看到他了 系好安全带
- Richard! - Yeah, I saw him. Strap in.
露意丝
Lois!
别乱跑
Don't move.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
理查
Richard!
我在努力 浪太大了
I'm trying! It's too choppy!
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
你们怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
谢谢
Thank you.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我必须回去
I have to go back.
你已经受伤了
You're hurt!
再见 露意丝
Goodbye, Lois.
氪星 超人的家乡
The technology on Krypton, Superman 's home world...
上面的科技是建立在操纵水晶上面的
...was based on manipulating the growth of crystals.
听起来像在变魔术
Sounds like hocus-pocus to me.
对我们这些原始的脑袋来说
Well, naturally, to the primitive mind, any sufficiently advanced technology...
超先进的科技跟变魔术没什么两样
...would be indistinguishable from magic.
但你想像一下： 城市、车辆 武器…
But imagine: Cities, vehicles, weapons...
整个大陆由此建立
...entire continents, all grown.
雷克斯？
Lex?
真的有几亿人会死吗？
Are billions of people really going to die?
是的
Yes.
雷克斯 怎么回事？
Lex, what's happening?
走走走 上直升机
Go, go, go. Get to the helicopter.
快出去
Go! Out, out! Now!
不不不 什么也别拿 快走
No, no, no, take nothing! Take nothing! Go, go!
好了
Got it.
这里
Here.
- 你做了什么？ - 对不起
- What did you do? - I'm sorry!
不
No!
- 你做了什么？ - 对不起
- What did you do? - I'm sorry!
看着点
Watch it.
- 让路 - 让路
- Clear a path. - Clear the way.
- 快点  - 1号急诊室
- Move! - Trauma One.
- 去哪？ - 1号急诊室
- Where we going? - Trauma One. Here it is.
看着点
Watch it!
好了
Got him!
我想我搞定了
Okay, I think I got it.
刺穿的部位在后背右下部
Penetrating side wound to right part of lower back.
没有出血
No hemorrhage.
200伏电击
Shock at 200.
够吗？ 他不是人类
Is that enough? He's not human.
好吧 充电到360伏
All right, charge to three, 360.
好了
Clear!
这太悲观了 派瑞
It's kind of morbid, Perry.
时刻做好准备
Always be prepared.
她怎么样？
How is she?
谢谢 谢谢宝贝
Thank you. Thanks, baby.
- 露意丝？ - 嗯
- Lois? - Yeah.
你想离开的话我们随时可走
We can leave whenever you're ready.
我是说
I mean...
你不需要留在这里
...you don't have to be here.
我还能去哪？
Where else would I be?
警察包围了那个区域
Police have surrounded the area in order to control thousands of visitors...
以便控制住数以千计的支持者
...who have arrived to show their support.
很多人携带标语
Many are carrying signs and banners...
我可以开车
I could drive.
过去几小时内无官方消息
No official announcements over the past few hours...
但内部不确切的消息说
...but unconfirmed reports from inside tell us...
超人昏迷中
...the Man of Steel lies in a coma...
自昨天情况一直没变
...his condition unchanged since he was admitted late yesterday.
- 医生们一直密切观察 - 外汇市场…
- Doctors have been vigilant in their... - Foreign exchange markets...
- 你们要去哪？ - 医院
- Where are you going? - To the hospital.
小心一点 那边一片混乱
I'd be careful down there, guys. It's a madhouse.
- 看来连找停车位都省了 - 你想我进得去吗？
- So much for parking. - Do you think I can get in?
你是露意丝·莲恩 他们会让你进去的
You're Lois Lane. They'll let you in.
我要和妈妈去
I wanna go with Mommy.
计程车
Taxi.
我在这里等
I'll be right here.
小心你的头 我们到了
Watch your head, okay? Here we go.
这边 莲恩小姐
This way, Miss Lane.
妈咪 他会好起来吗？
Mommy? Is he gonna get better?
- 我不知道 - 我想他好起来
- I don't know. - I want him to.
我喜欢他
I like him.
我也是
Me too.
我不知道你听不听得到
I don't know if you can hear me.
听说当人们
They say sometimes that when people are...
他们能听见你说的话
That sometimes they can hear you.
我不知道你听不听得到
I don't know if you can hear me.
但我想告诉你…
I wanted to tell you...
走吧 宝贝
Come on, honey.
请后退
Step back, please!
雷克斯 我们只有六颗椰子
Lex, we only have six of those!
六颗？
Six?
我愿意用三十万棵椰子
I would trade 300,000 coconuts...
加上你体内所有的血液
...and every ounce of your blood...
来换取一罐汽油
...for a quart of gasoline!
可是我们要吃什么？
But what will we have to eat?
(为什么世界需要超人)
你将会与众不同
You will be different.
有时候甚至会觉得自己被社会所被弃
Sometimes, you will feel like an outcast.
但是你永远不是孤独的
But you'll never be alone.
你将拥有我的力量
You will make my strength your own.
你会透过你的眼睛看见我的一生
You will see my life through your eyes...
就如我会透过我的眼睛看见你的一生
...as your life will be seen through mine.
儿子变成了父亲
The son becomes the father...
父亲又变成了儿子
...and the father becomes the son.
晚安
Good night!
我…
L...
我们会…
Will we see you?
再见到你吗？
Around?
我一直都在
I'm always around.
晚安 露意丝
Good night, Lois.